Good evening. March 17th board meeting.
Thank you all for coming down. We're
September uh 17th. What did I say? March
September. Um,
we're going to have the Pledge of
Allegiance and then we're going to have
the national anthem sung by our own
Talia Rosen, senior member of the
Soponic Honors Choir and president of
the Oceanside High School Swing Cars and
Select Choir. Please stand.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the
United States of America and to the
republic for which it stands, one nation
under God, indivisible, with liberty and
justice for all.
Say
[Music]
by the dawn early light.
What so proudly we held
at the twilight
last
stripes and bright stars
through the perilous
we
were so gallent
and the rockets
the bombs
in
proof through the night
that our flag was still there.
Oh, say
that star spangled
[Music]
for the land
of the free.
[Music]
A moment of silence, please.
If we can remember all our troops that
are out there fighting for our freedom,
our Nassau County Police Department, our
Roside Fire Department, all our first
responders, and of course all our family
friends that have with us.
Okay, please be seated. Continued
applause there for.
So, at this particular time, we turn the
board meeting over to uh Brian RLusco.
And Brian, if you can take us through
this uh high school government
representatives, that'd be great.
Definitely. Thank you. Uh yeah, I would
like to invite up Matthew Copel,
Jeremiah McDow, and Macy Bronner.
Thank you. First off, I would like by
saying the academic year began
successfully. Students are adjusting
well to their new classes and routines.
They also reconnecting with their
friends, adjusting to new school
policies, and getting involved in school
events. The in the incoming ninth
graders were welcomed through
orientation, our senior mentoring
classes, as well as building tours to
ease the transition to high school.
The fall sports season has launched with
our boys varsity soccer team winning 3 0
against Valley Stream, our varsity golf
team winning 9-0 against Smash Miniola,
and our varsity football team winning
51-6 against Unionale, and varsity boys
volleyball winning five sets against
Farmdale. Students are adapting well to
new electronic device policy. While it's
difficult for some, the classrooms feel
more focused with fewer distractions and
students are more engaged from the
number. Overall, the policy appears to
be successful, reducing interruptions
both inside and outside the classroom.
Our upcoming events start with
homecoming spirit week, which is one of
the best weeks at Oceanside High School
where every day there is a different
theme for students to dress up and show
their school spirit. Pep rally, where
the sports teams of the fall season are
introduced, and it's a real kickoff to
the season and gets everyone excited for
what's to come. saving the best for the
homecoming game, which everyone loves,
and being involved in showing our school
spirit. Those are scheduled for later
this month with strong student
anticipation for all events. Starting
this week, we have college rep visits
getting students ready for college
application process, as well as upcoming
senior meetings with our guidance
counselors, making sure everything is
complete and ready on Common App.
The school will be hosting its annual
club fair tomorrow after school in the
OS cafeteria, giving students the
opportunity to explore and join a
variety of extracurricular clubs.
Students are excited to learn about new
activities, connect with peers, and get
involved in the school community. The
high school is hosting its back to
school night on September 25th,
fostering communication between parents
and teachers as the students begin to
settle into their new schedules.
Uh, thank you. And I just have one more
quick thing to say. Hey, I would just
like to start by saying thank you to the
board and Dr. Harrington for being so
welcoming. This has been an honor so far
to be sitting here and I would just like
to talk quickly just about the
leadership cons the leadership
consortium I went to by Boseies for
other student leaders in Nassau County.
The first day was at the Boseies outdoor
campus where they had student
representatives participate in team
building activities which included
putting us on a rock climbing wall which
was a new experience for a lot of us.
The second day was learning about the
board of education and how it runs,
including a mock board meeting as well
as learning how to read the budget. It
was an awesome experience and will be
something I will carry for the rest of
my life. Thank you.
We have anybody else? That's it. Okay.
Thank you very much for that.
Um, now we're at uh 4B, which is the
2526 district goals. Dr. Harington.
Sure. Before I begin that portion of the
meeting, I just do want to acknowledge
our students. I think our board and
certainly our community at this point
knows we hear it best when we hear from
the students and I really do appreciate
the comments that were made about the
electronic device policy. And I have to
just say from day one, um, we had high
expectations for our students, but with
very good reasons. So, um, kudos to
everyone that was involved with that and
of course obviously our teachers who
helped support the policy, but the truth
of the matter is it's working because
the students get it and we do appreciate
very very much your understanding and
cooperation with that. So, thank you for
that and you will be role models for all
others to come know that. With that
being said, um, this is the year that
the time of year that we go over our
district goals that are established for
the new school year. I think our
community is very used to this process
because it's very cyclical. We begin um
by outlining new goals but how uh but
please know that they the process for
determining what those goals are going
to be are decided well before uh months
before actually and it's a collaborative
effort between teachers and
administrators and of course our
leadership team and ultimately our
district um a number of years ago
decided to put the the district goals in
a variety of buckets. Those included
curriculum and instruction, professional
learning, technology, community
outreach, facilities and operations,
communication, social and emotional
literacy, and meeting the needs of all
learners. We're going to review uh in
some detail what these goals are going
to be for this year. And please know
that throughout the year, we will find
different points at which to give
updates on how we're working towards
these goals. and then some point of the
in the spring, the latter very part of
the spring, we will give a final report
on how the the district has done in
meeting these goals. With that being
said, I'm going to ask the program to
begin by um in the area of curriculum,
instruction, and assessment. And I turn
the microphone over to Miss Pito.
Thank you, Dr. Harrington. At the core
of our work, we believe that curriculum,
instruction, and assessment must provide
a challenging, engaging, and meaningful
education for all students. Our 2025
2026 goals build on that belief and
focus on creating rigorous aligned
learning experiences across every grade
level. This year we are implementing
advanced placement seminar 10th grade
English. This is a course that gives
students early exposure to college level
research analysis and presentation
skills. Teachers have already completed
College Board endorsed training and work
together to design a curriculum that
prepares students for success in AP and
beyond. We are also expanding our
commitment to the New York State
Computer Science and Digital Fluency
Standards. This year, Kid Oyo, which is
a coding platform where students solve
realworld projectbased challenges, will
be fully integrated into grades six
through 8, building computational
thinking and problem solving skills at
the elementary level. This year we are
beginning the development of a digital
badge pathway through our digital
discoveries program which introduces
students to computer science, digital
citizenship and safety and creative
technology applications. Students will
be able to earn badges as they build
their skills in grades one through six.
Together these initiatives create a
strong foundation for digital fluency.
In literacy, we are refining
workstations for our small group
instruction. This promotes foundational
reading skills, fluency in particular,
in partnership with our consultant and
national expert, Dr. Chris Parker. These
efforts are part of our response to
intervention and multi-tiered systems of
support framework that's commonly known
as RTI MTSS. and our means. This is our
means to ensure that all students get
the right support at the right time so
they can grow into strong readers. We
are also moving into the final phase of
the elementary program words their way.
We are adding additional engaging
evidence-based practices that strengthen
phonics, spelling, and vocabulary.
Teacher leaders have worked throughout
the summer to enhance curricular
resources and we are providing
professional development to support the
new additions and to further the high
quality literacy instruction taking
place across all classrooms.
In mathematics, we are introducing the
New York State Education Department
numeracy briefs to all K through2 staff.
These researchbased guides define what
strong math instruction looks like and
offer practical strategies for building
students mathematical thinking across
every grade level. And for our youngest
learners, we are adopting the BGAN
screener in universal preK, giving
teachers actionable data to inform class
placement and personalized instruction
from day one.
Together, these initiatives create a
clear through line, aligning challenging
and meaningful learning experiences from
preK all the way through graduation so
every single student in Oceanside is
prepared to thrive. I'd like to
acknowledge our curriculum and
instruction directors, our principles,
and our faculty who work with expertise,
passion, and commitment to bring these
goals to life and keep Oceanside a model
of innovative and outstanding education.
Our commitment to rigorous learning goes
hand in hand with supporting every
student. Our executive director of
special education, Miss Tracy Murray,
will now share our goals for meeting the
needs of all learners.
Thank you, Mrs. Pito. And good evening,
everyone. At the core of Oceanside's
mission is our belief that every program
must meet the needs of all learners so
that every student can reach their
highest potential with equitable
opportunities across the district. This
year we are moving forward with several
key initiatives in special education.
Phase two of our multiensory reading
program spire will deepen impact by
enhancing datadriven instruction,
building team capacity through training,
and aligning with Dr. Chris Parker's
MTSS model for progress monitoring. We
are also reviewing universal screening
tools for our special class students to
ensure stronger alignment to growth and
access in less restrictive environments.
For our integrated co-eing program, we
are completing the final phase of our
elementary paradigm, expanding
collaboration with the early learning
center, and beginning phase one of
secondary ICT with a focus on data
collection and program review. Through
our culturally responsive education and
equity advisory, CRE, we are advancing
phase two of authentic grading and
assessment at the secondary level and
strengthening responsive classroom
practices in elementary schools to
support belonging and academic success.
At Oceanside High School Castleton, we
are enhancing postsecary planning by
expanding CTE pathways, internships, and
personalized guidance so that every
student leaves with clear with a clear
plan for their future. Together, these
initiatives reflect our belief that we
are always better together and united in
our commitment to meeting the needs of
all learners. I'd now like to introduce
Dr. D. Rosa who will share our
professional learning and social and
emotional literacy goals.
Thank you, Mrs. Murray. Our ongoing
commitment to professional learning
reflects our belief that when we invest
in our staff, we invest in the success
of every student. This year, we are
proud to build on that promise with
several exciting initiatives that
strengthen teaching, learning, and
student well-being across Oceanside.
One of our major areas of focus is
executive functioning. These are the
skills that help students succeed not
only in life, but in school, but in
life. Time management, organization,
planning, and self-regulation form the
foundation that allows students to meet
academic challenges and grow as
independent, capable individuals.
This year, we are providing professional
development that helps staff integrate
executive function strategies more
intentionally into daily instruction. By
strengthening these skills, we are
preparing our students not only for
strong academic outcomes, but also for
the demands of college careers and their
future lives. We are also very excited
to highlight our new partnership with
Long Island University. Through this
collaboration, we have welcomed seven
teaching fellows who are certified
teachers and recent graduates. Each
fellow is placed in one of our
elementary schools where they provide
direct support in reading and math while
also engaging in a year of intensive
professional development under the
direction of Miss Jessica Keegan, our
director of elementary teaching and
learning. The fellows receive weekly
coaching and mentoring and have the
opportunity to work side by side with
our staff. This initiative is a true
partnership. It enhances the growth of
our elementary students through
additional support and it strengthens
the teaching profession by giving these
fellows a chance to refine their
practice in a supportive environment.
Finally, we continue to pri prioritize
social and emotional literacy. We know
that our students need more than
academic preparation. They also need
strategies to navigate the stressors of
everyday life. Our multi-tered approach
to dialectical behavioral therapy
provides students with concrete tools to
manage emotions, cope with challenges,
and build healthy relationships.
Staff at every level have been trained
in these practices and they continue to
weave them into the daily life of our
schools. This work reflects our belief
that social and emotional growth is
inseparable from academic growth in
preparing students to thrive.
Together, these initiatives reflect
Oceanside's unwavering commitment to
excellence in teaching and learning. By
investing in our staff, strengthening
executive functioning, and supporting
social and emotional literacy, we are
providing our students the skills to
succeed not only today, but in every
step of their future. It is now my
pleasure to introduce Anna Polloccast,
our executive director of technology.
Thank you, Dr. D. Roza. At the heart of
our technology goal is a simple idea.
Technology should never replace good
teaching. It should strengthen it. Our
goal is for technology to be seamlessly
woven into classroom best practices,
helping teachers do what they already do
well while giving students new ways to
learn and create. One major area of
focus is artificial intelligence. We're
entering the second year of our K
through2 AI initiative where we are
deepening our use of magic school and
introducing Google Gemini. This phase is
about more than just new tools. It's
about making sure AI is thoughtfully
embedded in lessons, helping teachers
plan and students learn in meaningful
ways. We are providing professional
development for staff and setting clear
expectations for AI use. Our curriculum
will include cons instruction on
artificial intelligence and developing
skills to use it both effectively and
ethically ethically.
Our hope and dream is to foster critical
thinking, encourage responsible
decision-making, and prepare our
students for the digital world they're
inheriting. Another important goal this
year is strengthening literacy using new
educational software. We are introducing
LitLab, an online platform in grades K
through six.
This program is aligned with the science
of reading and provides resources for
teaching phonics, fluency, and practice
with decodable texts. Lit lab gives
teachers more tools for small groupoup
instruction and creates engaging
opportunities for our youngest learners
to build confidence and a strong
foundation as readers. Together, these
initiatives reflect our commitment to
ensuring that technology in our schools
is not about gadgets or trends, but
about giving every student the skills,
opportunity, and confidence they need to
succeed. And now, Dr. Harrington will
share the community outreach and
communication goals. Thank you. It is no
surprise that our school district feels
very strongly in continually to reach
out to our community in a number of ways
and to help them grow intellectually,
socially, and rec recreationally. We are
we continue to be incredibly proud of
the work of our OSD parent university
which is really something that is a
collaborative effort between our uh our
our team led by Miss Pito and our parent
members. This year in particular um we
want to focus on workshops that support
parents in raising healthy well-balanced
children. So there will be topics that
will include and be aligned to the
current research on cell phone and
social media use uh as we move certainly
to of cell phone free schools. But in
addition based on the survey we
completed in June of 2025 there will be
sessions on artificial intelligence
responsive classroom as well as
executive function. And again I thank
the efforts of all the members of the
parent university committee. In
addition, in terms of outreach, special
education is continually finding ways to
reach out to its parent population.
We're going to continue to offer
workshops that address the unique needs
of students of parents with students
with disabilities, but we're going to be
hosting workshops including three
preschool focused workshops as well as
monthly parent trainings specifically
for families of students in the sales
and ACE programs.
Communication is always a a belief of
ours that we continually look for ways
to improve that. And to that end, the uh
community is well aware that the board
transitioned a number of years ago to a
digital platform that you're looking at
on the screens above uh known as board
docs. This communication uh device has
given the board much more um ability to
be accessible and transparent to our
community in an easier and more
efficient uh way. We are hoping to move
to board docs upgrade which will be
known as the diligent community
platform. Uh we're just waiting for them
to reach out to us to say they're ready
to take us on as we transition to that
next stage. And again it's just to
improve on a program we currently have
in place. And finally, in terms of
communication, a goal again of the
special education department is
continually to find ways to improve
access to parents and that will include
going completely paperless. This gives
um parents an opportunity to receive
documents in a very very timely fashion.
Uh which of course is very very
important given um the need to have
those documents to make informed
conversations with the with the teachers
and administrators. Uh with that I turn
uh the rest of the program over to Dr.
Kley.
Thank you Dr. Harrington. In the area of
facilities and operations, the district
has been undergoing some important
capital improvements over the last few
years. One of the goals this year uh at
school 6 is to reclaim space that was
previously occupied by an external
organization. We have already begun
working on this goal that will
ultimately support our early learning
center with five additional
instructional spaces for students. The
work includes new flooring, a new
ceiling grid, new univvents, and brand
new cubbies for storage, which will be
ready next year. With the community's
ongoing support, this past summer, our
two capital projects have both begun.
Over at school number three, the turf is
now fully installed for our students to
enjoy. At our high school, our the
tennis courts are now fully completed
with their renovation. The goal for the
turf projects is to have both the
baseball and softball turf installed and
ready for the upcoming spring season for
our student athletes. With respect to
our other project known as phase five,
the goal is to have the interior
foundation and shell of the new brick
and mortar in place as well as beginning
the reconstruction of the existing
classrooms to convert them into a new
auto shop as well as a modernized wood
shop.
The district is near full completion
with its implementation of the energy
performance contract which includes 11
energy conservation measures which
include LED interior and exterior
lights, solar panels on all school
campuses, building weatherization
improvements, steam trap upgrades, plug
load controls, boiler burner controls,
among others. This year, the goal is to
fully close out the EPC while also
exploring ideas and proposals for a
potential second phase of an energy
performance contract. Once completed and
closed out with the state education
department, all projects will begin will
be will bring additional building aid to
back to the district, which will help
offset revenue in future years to reduce
the financial burden on our taxpaying
community. And finally, in the area of
safety and security, as we do each year,
several professional development
opportunities are in place for all
district-wide security personnel. This
includes upcoming trainings on CPR, AED,
stop the bleed, situational awareness,
and tabletop exercises. With each
training led by external partners,
including the Oceanside Fire Department,
Northwell Health, Nassau County Police,
the Department of Homeland Security, and
of course, our partners, the Alteras
Consulting Group. The district keeps
security as a top priority and is fully
committed to training all staff with the
most up-to-date information and best
practices.
Thank you, Dr. Kley. So, I think um I
hope the board and community can
appreciate the breadth and depth of
these goals and um it's obvious then I
would hope that these cannot be done in
isolation. They must be a collaborative
effort and we really take very seriously
the concept of Oceanside schools better
together. I would like to let the
community know that the full document
that goes into detail just as we did
discussed this evening is a document
that uh is and will be available on our
district website. They will live uh
there all year long and you can hold us
accountable for any one of those goals
at any given time. But as I had said
earlier, we will be reviewing
continually as we do where we are in
progress towards achieving these goals.
At this time, Mr. Dmbrosio, I'll
entertain any questions any board
members may have. Any board member would
like to have any questions regarding go
ahead Mr. Kaplan
on slide number five under professional
learning it has the second bullet is
executive function professional
development is that learning how to work
with students that have executive
function issues or is we talking
something different?
It's for the general um student
population. So all students learn
strategies to help them with things such
as organization, time management, even
studying. So, it really is a general set
of skills that are supportive of that.
You're welcome.
Anybody else? I just have one question
for Dr. Hley on the EPC contract.
Eventually, we'd be able to get the cost
savings that we that are current. I mean
that I mean we have we have all our
schools almost running basically.
Can you elaborate on that on
on our elementary schools and our high
school? Ultimately the answer would be
yes with the um only thing is that two
of our schools um the nine complex and
the high school are not fully online
with the connection to the solar panel
grid. So you don't have um we need at
least a year's worth of data to know how
much we had typically budgeted for
ultimately into how much we're saving.
But we do we did see a substantial
reduction in utility savings with that.
We don't have a full year's worth of all
of the components because we're not
fully completed. Um part of the EPC is
um the district gets what's known as an
MNV measurement and verification
guaranteed for three years by the
contractor. Obviously once the
completion is fully completed that
starts the clock of the three years. So
obviously because we're not fully
completed we have not begun that point.
Is it possible to say that during the
day our elementary schools the smaller
buildings are running almost free but we
can't
uh depending
nice thing to say but I don't know
depending on the exposure to the sun uh
and and how much is built up and Mr.
Transom I know you can help me with this
um it it does depend but that has been
um a reality for sure.
So that can that Mr.
Yes, you actually could. Uh, but we'd
have to set it up so we can test it over
two months or so. So, we have to be able
to gather the data because it we did
prove it with the uh uh less solar uh uh
last year. We had an electrical savings
that was uh correct me if I'm wrong,
five or $600,000,
something like that.
Yep.
So, we know that that little bit is
going to be exponentially a lot more
when the middle school and high school
go in. It's primarily in the solar, but
the weatherization and the lighting was
a big savings and that's what's measured
in that 600,000.
That's a that's a significant savings
and I' I'd bank on that anytime with the
money that we spent.
Perfect. Thanks a lot, Mr. Transit. And
Mr.
Thank you, Mr. Sol.
Yeah. Uh Dr. Kley, just to clarify, the
beauty of the EPC
uh contract was that
any cost savings that we incurred
because of the contract would go to pay
the vendors for the cost of making all
the upgrades. And then once we're done
with them, any revenue then goes back
into reducing the cost of our operation
budget.
That is correct. with one um additional
benefit
once. So the project what you're saying
is the project is self- sustaining which
you're absolutely the project pays for
itself. Ultimately the savings that come
from this the the utilities the electric
etc ultimately reduce how much we need
to budget in subsequent budget years for
utility codes. But the additional
benefit is because this energy
performance contract is recognized by
the state education department as a
capital project. We the benefits as a
self- sustaining project of bringing
additional building aid which is
approximately 40 cents of the dollar for
us.
I just wanted to clarify that for people
to understand the the beauty of this EPC
contract. It was a very creative and
unique idea. Um thank you Dr. Harrington
for bringing that to us because I think
you discovered some other districts that
were doing it before us and um it it was
a it was really a great suggestion
uh because No, it does. It avoids all
these having to bond and all this other
stuff. We're we're doing it slowly, but
we're paying for it ourselves through
our savings.
That's correct.
Thank you.
We could have done that work without Mr.
Powaskki, of course, every morning
coming to us about solar power.
Uh so we're going to go now to uh 4C,
which the enrollment for uh September of
2025. Dr. Harrington.
Yes, thank you. So, um I believe we will
have our numbers up there, but um what I
do want to point out, this is a report
that we make every September obviously
to give the board and community an
update where we are comparing to where
we were last year at this time.
Obviously, this is a fluid document. I
have to tell you it literally changes
every day. Um we but I look at it on a
monthly basis. When there are
significant u points that must be made
to the board, I will bring it to the
board. But suffice to say, as you look
at this, um, if you look at the just
the, uh, the the top bucket, those are
the elementary schools from UPK through
9E. And as you can see, we're two
students more than we were in the
beginning of September 204. I am going
to address the kindergarten numbers at
the end of this, but just know um,
pretty much we stayed on track across
each and each building. I also want to
remind the board that we had done an
enrollment study a number of years ago
and then we did an update to it when we
were doing the capital reserve project.
I traced those numbers and I have to say
in some cases they were spot on like the
exact number that they predicted um we
were going to have in certain schools I
think nine was the one they got it spot
on. I don't know how they do it. But the
good news is that we made certain
decisions a couple of years ago that we
recognized that there were some
inequities in numbers in our buildings
and that's very apparent when you look
at the the the day the data there, but
that it wasn't going to grow to a
problem where we really needed to do
something I'm going to put in quotes
drastic in order to deal with the
enrollment numbers. So we um we've
stayed pretty much status quo from last
year to this year at the elementary
level and the middle school are there
was a a little bit of an uptick but that
really just depends on the cohorts that
actually wind up being in um in the
school at that particular time. But we
now have a middle school of 831
students. Um which if you know anything
about middle school students, it's a lot
of middle school students in one place.
Uh kudos to our middle school principal
and and staff who make that be a magical
place. and our high school. Uh we took a
little bit of a dip from from um where
we started in September of 24. I will
say again, I don't have hard data to
back this up, but we do get a number of
students that choose to go to private
school for their high school years. And
that's typically what we see. And I have
to tell you, somewhere's around
December, January, February, all of a
sudden kids start to trickle back in or
a couple of grades later. But more or
less, um that's where we took a little
bit of a dip. Castleton has been
relatively constant. We always start the
school year with approximately 3540
students. We typically end uh in June
closer to 50 60 and that's just the
nature of of the way that program works
and the process in that regard. So, in
total, in terms of where we are as a
district, we began September of 2024
with 5,173
students, and we began this September
with 5,155
students. So, you know, give or take 20
students. We're still on track to be
relatively consistent in terms of our
enrollment. In terms of the breakdowns
by schools, that's the next slide you
see here. Um I think what you want what
speaks um at the elementary level I
think these numbers do speak for
themselves in the sense that they also
match where we've been um in terms of
the enrollment study. So I'm happy about
that. Uh and again consistent across the
board in terms of kindergarten.
Something I do want to point out
publicly. I did have this conversation
with the PTA as well earlier in the
month, but we did see an uptick of
kindergarten students that enrolled
literally within the last week of
school, if not the first couple of days
of school. And that really does set up a
problem for us because at that point,
our students have been assigned
teachers. The parents and families know
who the teachers are. uh and to undo
that is something that um is really not
a practice that we believe is in the
best interest of our students, our
families or or or or our teachers. So,
um we deal with what we what we're
given. So, the guideline and remember we
do have class- size guidelines. We did a
whole presentation on that in the
spring. That presentation still lives on
our website. You're welcome to take a
look at that. But the guideline for
kindergarten is 22 students. I remind
everyone that we have a practice here of
one teacher and an aid in every single
classroom. So there are two adults for
every 22 students. I will say that u
because of the enrollments that came to
us late in the year, there are numbers
of classrooms at our kindergarten that
went as high as 23. We uh took a close
look at that. We are monitoring as we as
we go along where the need and support
may be may be needed. And I can assure
the community that where and when we
find that need, we will meet that need.
Um, but at the end of the day, that's
the way our numbers break down and I
will answer any questions any board
member may have.
Do I have any questions from the board?
Laura, yes.
Sorry. Um, I just had a question about
the UPK. I noticed our numbers are is a
little bit down.
Um, did we have a weight list this year
or
We did not. We did not have a wait list.
While I can't say I know this for a fact
because I don't have the hard data, but
what what we hear and what we what we
believe is that we have many many more
um double working families. Um so the
the hours that our prek provides is just
not enough for a good majority of our of
our parents. So they do have to choose
an alternative where they have a longer
day.
Okay. Thank you.
But I will say Dr. Anthony, I did feel a
question about when does registration in
school and I say we're open, you know,
for the entire school year. So, it's 365
days on registrations. We get uh kids
coming into our district the week or two
before and a month later. So, it's it's
a little bit hard on doing it, but I
know we're doing a good job on trying to
to manage the numbers that we do get the
last
we we changed the process a couple of
years ago. remember it used to be that
teachers were parents were told who the
teachers were going to be for the
upcoming school year in June when they
actually left. Um and um that caused
real havoc because we do have a lot of
in andout numbers over the course of of
the summer. Um so we made a commitment
that we would wait till a certain uh
date. Parents are notified as close to a
week before school um when um who the
teachers actually are. And of course by
that point the teachers and are hired
and you we we try to hire the best of
the best obviously. Um so it becomes
much much harder the latter part of
August to hire what we believe is a
standard for Oceanside in terms of the
teaching staff. So, we stick to that
deadline, but once those names of the
teachers go out, unless there was a
tremendously dramatic uh shift in
numbers, which is unlikely, uh we we
stick to the the decisions that were
made at the time that the teachers were
announced.
Yes, Sandy.
Yeah. I want to go back to the UPK topic
for a minute. Okay.
Um my my question is,
uh I know that we had no waiting list up
to the In other words, we had a deadline
where everybody had to register by. So,
anyone who registered by the deadline
was accommodated. Um, after that
deadline, did we get any late
registrants that we were able to
accommodate or
Yes, we we had many late registrants and
they were all accommodated.
They were all accommodated. Correct.
Okay. And then my other question is, did
the state give us any new money at all
this year?
Not this year. Um, obviously we're we
believe that there's a true commitment
to early childhood education. I also
believe the state is collecting data
that they're asking from us on on on the
results of that and I think we have some
really clear evidence that our students
who have attended UPK particularly in
Oceanside who then come to our
kindergarten um are certainly um well um
prepared for kindergarten and and
beyond. So I believe the state is
gathering that data and once they have
all of that I do believe that the the
resources would be there to increase
even you know the aotment and we have
the space for it and as Dr. Kley
mentioned earlier building the
additional classrooms so we have the
space we're very very fortunate that's
really not the case in most districts. I
know that they had allocated us money
based on um well I know they
accommodated 285 seats last year but the
money that they give us this year is
going to be based on 273.
No no no no that that's not the way
it's still the same pool of money.
Correct. And it was 287 that they they
allowed us last year and it was 287 this
year.
So they don't reduce the pool unless the
money unless the money goes elsewhere. I
can't speak for that, but barring the
fact that it's unlikely we would have at
least 287, of course, we're hoping for
more.
And we're also hoping for some realistic
inflationary increases, too.
Correct. Correct.
Okay. Um, and then I have another
question for you, and I just want to get
back down here to the actual elementary
enrollment by building.
Correct.
And down to the kindergarten. Um, the to
me it seems like a very large number for
school three and school eight
in kindergarten. um are we going to
we're preparing for that for next year
as they go
those numbers. So the what what you're
pointing out so if you look at where it
says kindergarten we do track by home
school we don't place kids but we track
it to to see where long-term where the
trends are going to be and those trends
with school three and definitely school
eight being the highest um are are
consistent with what the enrollment
study has said. So we we have that
prepared.
So we're prepared. I guess my question
is are we prepared for that at school
three and school eight uh when they move
first grade next year?
Those those numbers are are are
consistent with what again the
enrollment study said. But yes, if you
look at school 8 grade one this year is
only 60 kids. If all of these
kindergarten students remain with us
that's that will be a big shift and then
we will increase at the appropriate time
the number of sections. So the answer is
even school school five is on the high
end of
Yeah, we Yes. Actually, yes.
I just want to make sure that when they
hit first grade that you know we're
prepared for this and that uh we're
going to have the space for this and
yes
in those buildings
right now. Right now we're prepared.
There's no surprises. Okay.
Correct.
Thank you.
Okay. Uh we're at 5A which is
opportunity to comment on agenda items
only. Any audience member wishing to
make a comment on an item that is on
tonight's agenda can do so at this time.
Anyone wishing to make a comment on an
item not on tonight's agenda will have
the opportunity to do so later in the
agenda. While New York State Law does
not require us to hold a public comment
period on agenda items, this board of
education choose to do so because we
believe it is important to get input
from community members on the board's
agenda items. Please note that the board
is here to listen. While everyone is
encouraged to share their comments,
please keep in mind that this is not
designed to be a question and answer
session. Again, comments should be
directed towards the chair of the
meeting, which is me. Anyone wishing to
speak should come up to the microphone.
Clearly state your name and your child's
school.
And do we have anybody right now at this
time? It's only on agenda items only.
Seeing none, we're going to go to 6A,
which is the approval of minutes for the
August 27th, 2025. I'll take a motion.
Motion.
St.
Second.
Second. Sandy. Any questions or
comments? All in favor? I.
Any opposed? Any abstension? Motion
passes. I'll take an acceptance for
financial reports, treasures report,
transfer of funds, and internal claims,
auditors, review of warrants. I'll take
a motion.
I make that motion.
I'll move it. I'll second it. Excuse me.
Okay. Any questions or comments? All in
favor?
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes.
7A. Approval of use of facilities the
Oceanside Wrestling Club. I'll take a
motion.
Move it.
Second.
Second. All in favor?
I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. Approve to declare technology
equipment surplus. I'll take a motion.
I'll make that motion.
Sandy.
I second.
Moore. Any questions or comments or
I have one question. Okay.
I just want I I want to make sure that
any parts or pieces that we could
utilize we we have. That is correct.
Before we dispose of it,
that's correct.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay. So, we have U Sandy and Laura. Um,
any questions or comments? All in favor?
I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. And we're going to approve the
declare uh approval to declare textbook
surplus.
Move it.
Take a motion, which is Bob.
Second.
Dawn. Any question or comments?
I have a question. I'm sorry. Okay. My
question on the books is none of them
are are able to be donated to um any
other uh charitable organization to ut
utilize. They're badly damaged or
they're outdated. Is that the case,
Mrs. Pito? No.
Yeah. Yeah. No, that is the case. And
quite honestly, the cost involved in in
transferring we we've attempted that in
the past. We thought that would make
sense. They're not usable textbooks.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay. Okay. So, we have any questions or
comments? All in favor?
I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. And we're going to take an
approval to accept the donation of a
violin.
I'll take a motion.
Motion.
I'll second it.
So, we're good. Got that still in Sandy.
Any questions or comments? God bless.
All in favor?
Any opposed? Any abstensions? And the
motion passes. Thank you for the violin
donation and approval to accept
donation. Boardman Feld Penn. I'll take
a motion.
I make that motion.
Laura, a second. Bob. Any questions or
comments? All in favor? I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. It's to the people in the
audience. It's it's it's a it's a banner
um with a pennant. Looks like a Yankees
banner, but only says Boardman on it.
So, it's pretty cool.
From the 1940s.
1940s. Maybe we could put that up on a
website. Uh 8A personnel uh professional
personnel recommendations. I'll take a
motion to approve.
Okay.
Don.
Okay. Um
Stu,
any questions or comments? All in favor?
I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. Contract approval for the
non-represented employees. I'll take a
motion.
I'll make that motion.
Sandy,
I second.
Laura, any questions or comments? All in
favor? I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. I'll take a motion for to
approve civil service personnel
recommendations as submitted.
I'll move it.
Okay. Bob.
Second.
Don. Any questions or comments? All in
favor?
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes.
Mr. Danzer, if I may, I just have to
point out we have two approvals of
resignations um this evening. One is
Mary Conlin, the school nurse at our
high school. I just do want to go on
record saying that nurse Conlin is
really just quite superior and um she
will be missed. Um she is taking a
position in a neighboring school
district, but um she really is the best
of the best and and we will definitely
be missing her. We had the pleasure of
having Brandon Rooney as our head
custodian at our high school for the
past two years. We knew when we hired
him that we wouldn't have him for too
long because he did have his sights on
an advanced position. We didn't think it
would happen as quickly as it did and
primarily it did because he's going
somewhere not at that title but with
promise to achieve that title. Um but we
anyone who knows our high school has
known that his it has never looked as
good. So um he has set the bar high. I
have promised this board and the
principal of the high school that we
will settle for nothing less. Uh but we
certainly wish him um equally as as a
wonderful successful journey in in his
next in his next leg.
We want 8D which is motion to approve
the hourly employees recommendation is
submitted. I'll take a motion.
Motion.
St.
Second.
Sandy. Any questions or comments? All in
favor?
I.
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes. Dr. Harington. Anything? And
I'll take a motion to approve it. Uh,
docker employee recommendation as
submitted. Take a motion.
I make a motion.
Laura,
a second.
Uh, all in uh any question or comments?
All in favor?
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes.
Um 9A recommendation for the U make a
motion to approve the recommendation of
a CEPS
chairperson that's submitted. I'll take
a motion.
Move it.
Dawn.
Second.
And Stu. Any questions or comments? All
in favor?
I I
Any opposed? Any abstensions? Motion
passes.
We're going to go now to 10 A, which is
items for action. A motion approved the
2526 Oceanside School District goals.
I'll take a motion.
I'll make that motion.
Second.
I second.
Okay. Any questions or comments? All in
favor? I.
Any opposed?
Any abstensions? Motion passes.
opportunity for the superintendent of
schools.
Yes, thank you. Just Yes, thank you, Mr.
D. Just a couple of things. Um, again,
the school year got off to just an
amazing start. It's hard to believe
we're well into the flow of things. Uh,
but that really is because we just have
an amazing um faculty, staff, uh,
community, our students. It's it really
is a combined effort. So, kudos to
everyone who helped make the opening so
very smooth. Um, please refer to our
district calendar. There is chalk full
of events. Uh just a couple that I'll
mention uh coming up in the near future.
Uh we do have our thesian review which
is always a highlight tomorrow evening.
But uh first for the first time we're
doing a a a Disney brunch, Disney
princess brunch, excuse me. Uh this
coming Saturday. Uh it's going to be
absolutely adorable. But we're doing it
as a fundraiser for our marching band
and thebs students who will be attending
um uh a privileged opportunity to
participate uh in in a program in Disney
World uh this coming May. Can't wait. Um
but it is a first of what will be many
fundraisers. So we really hope our
community comes out and supports u bring
your little ones, boys and girls allowed
um because we're going to have just a
great time that there's information on
our website about that. Um, our students
did briefly mention our athletic season
which has kicked off. It's in full
swing, but this Friday night uh is our
second football game. We won our first
one 51-6 if people weren't uh weren't
aware of that. Uh, but this Friday night
is our first um game under the lights 6
pm. Come out and support our students.
Um, what speaking of the students, they
did mention our club fair at our high
school tomorrow. And I just want to just
say publicly that I continue to be
completely um amazed by the support that
this board and community and then the
teachers who are willing to step up as
adviserss of our clubs. We have so many
diverse clubs. There's just there's no
end to the things that our students can
be involved in. We certainly do clubs at
our elementary level as well, but I I
just say what we do in our high school
is by far um non-comparable to anything
else that I've seen. So looking forward
to another great year with that as well.
Um, and this is also back to school uh
days as was mentioned also by our
students and I know our parents really
look forward to an opportunity to meet
with our our teachers and and faculty uh
in in that environment as well as well
as our PTA barbecues and welcome back uh
uh lunches and breakfast barbecues and
all those things that these great PTA
people do um to really make it feel like
a wonderful community and that is
certainly what it
So that concludes my report. Mr.
Dembrosia,
thank you. Dr. Harrington 12A, we have a
board of education report. I just like
to start off by saying uh Eric Aby's the
president of Aquanis is uh couldn't make
it tonight, but he'd want you he wanted
us to know that uh the installation
dinner for the Aquanis is going to be on
October 16th at uh Temple Voda, and it's
going to be a great time. We we usually
get a lot of people there. So, if you
get the opportunity, please uh send in
your checks. And we'd like to see a lot
of people in the community. This year,
we're honoring uh Anthony Puma from uh
with the sorry, Michael Puma uh for the
uh Heart of Gold and Dr. Clickman Rogers
for his service uh that she's been doing
a wonderful job at the middle school. Uh
seeing that, I'm done. Uh Mr. Kaplan.
Yeah. I'd like to just uh take this
moment. I read on LinkedIn. And I'd like
to congratulate our uh Castleton
principal, Dr. uh Frankie Simmons, on
def successfully defending his
dissertation. I'd like to say
congratulations to you. Well done.
One step closer to being a doctor,
right? Not not quite there yet, but he's
that that's why I pulled back the
doctor. I was like, "Okay, he got you
got to a certain point.
He's closer, but he's not quite there
yet. We'll get in there."
Okay. Anybody else?
Yeah. Show. Uh, I first of all, I'd like
to thank the administration and the
teachers and staff, everybody who helped
us have a very successful opening to
school. This was really pretty seamless.
Um, you know, a few little glitches here
and there, but it was the quietest start
to a year uh that I can remember in a
long time. But I want to especially
compliment and thank um our students uh
for their level of cooperation and
maturity with regard to the cell phone
policy. I you amaze me. Um I I had a
feeling it was going to work and I and
it's working because of of your level of
of maturity and uh you're a special
group of kids at the high school and in
the middle school and the elementary
school. So, I just want to congratulate
you because it's just tremendous
how well you have adapted.
Okay. Thank you, Mr. Shaw and Laura.
Good. And Bob Transom. Good. And Mr.
Morris.
Uh, I thank you, Mr. Chair. I didn't
think I'd be on tonight, but
unfortunately, I missed the last board
meeting. And there's one thing I wanted
to say. Uh first of all I want to
congratulate a special congratulations
to Diane Pvido for organizing a most
successful new staff orientation
program. It was very well done and if
they announced it at the last board
meeting no one told me. So again
congratulations.
I forgot about we mentioned it. Don you
Brian is there anything else that you'd
like to bring up about the high school
that you might have forgotten? When will
the next board meeting?
Exactly. We'll have a couple of plays
you can uh give us some stuff on. Brian,
anything good? We'll get there. Okay.
So, at the end, this is as we come to
the end, uh this is opportunity to
comment on non-aggenda items. Next is
public comment on non-aggenda items.
This is the opportunity for anyone who
wants to make a comment on any item
that's not on tonight's agenda. As I
previously mentioned, state law does not
require us to hold public comment,
period. But this board of education does
so because we believe it's important to
provide this forum to hear from our
community members about our concerns and
issues. Having said that, please note
that the board is here to listen.
Comment should be directed towards the
chair of the meeting which is me. While
everyone is encouraged to share this
comment, please remember that this is
not designed to be a question and answer
session. Someone has a question that be
that can be quickly answered, we'll do
so. Otherwise, the appropriate personnel
will follow up on any issue. Lastly,
please remember that the board cannot
and will not discuss matters related to
staff or students in public. Anybody
wishing to come up speak to the
microphone, please please state your
name and your child's school. Thank you
for your cooperation. Is there anybody
that would like to come up? I see a boy
scout back there. I was wondering what
he was doing.
Oh,
that's great. Good for you.
Would you like to come up and tell us
about a little bit? We're good.
Little shy. Okay. Very good. Is there
anybody else that would like to come up
to the microphone and have something to
say?
If not, seeing nothing, I'll take a
motion.
Motion to adjurnn. Second.
Everybody safe. Drive home.